this problem requires us to
use a loop to remove and print
each element of our names array from
first
to last when the names array is empty
when we've removed all of the elements
then we need to stop looping
so first let's create our loop you can
see our names array initialize on line
one
is an array of strings
there is a ruby method that allows us to
remove the first
element of an array and that's the array
shift method
let me actually comment out our loop for
now
we'll print our names array then call
the shift method on the array and print
it again
just to see what this looks like
the first element of our array sally has
been removed
the return value of calling shift on an
array
is that first element itself so we can
print that as well
[Music]
the first element which is removed from
the array
is also returned
so now that we know how shift mutates
our array
and what it returns we can actually use
this in our loop
since we want to remove the elements of
this array from first to last
we can call shift on our names array
and the problem requires that we also
output this element
since we know that the shift method
returns the element it removes
we can simply call puts
now we need a break condition here
first let's also print out the array
after
we execute the code on line four and
then break
after one iteration
[Music]
we removed sally from the array and
output it
appropriately so we're on the right
track
[Music]
but we want to iterate through this loop
more than one time
so let's think about when we want to
break
the problem description tells us that we
want to break when the name's array is
empty
so after we've removed all of these
elements
we can call the array empty method
on our names array and that will return
a boolean
if it returns true we'll break out of
our loop
otherwise we'll continue to loop so now
let's see what we've got
[Music]
and you can see that we have the
appropriate output
[Music]
just to see what our names array looks
like after running through the loop
we can print that out on line eight and
run the code again
[Music]
and as you can see on the last line of
our output that's now an
empty array
[Music]
now if you didn't happen to know the
array empty method
you could also do something like this
you could compare the size of the array
to zero if the size of the array is zero
then we know that it's empty
[Music]
so this also causes our code to run
appropriately
now how would we handle it if we instead
wanted to remove
the elements of the array from last to
first
so in this instance what if we wanted to
remove
henry then lisa joe and sally
there's also an array method named pop
and it works similarly to shift except
that it removes the last element of the
array and returns it
so now let's run our code and see if
we're removing the elements in reverse
order
[Music]
and we are